let me do a really simple example next I
want to do the limit of a constant as X
goes to a value of a so for example I'm
going to bring up a graph here this is
the choice where my constant was one
what is the limit of one as X goes to a
well it doesn't matter where I am on
here if I if I want to talk about this
point right here the limit as you get
close to this point is one limit as you
get close to this point is one this
point every point you could get close
two the height of it's always one so no
matter what it is it's the value of one
or in the generic case when arbitrary C
here I'm going to say the limit is equal
to C okay here's sort of the next most
complicated function not a constant this
time it's the variable X so this is the
graph of a straight line it looks a
little bit like this and notice if I was
to do the limit as we get close to.5
here 0.5 is just equal to well 0. five
if I got close to the value of one up
here well that's going to have this
height of one over here if I go up to
two it's going to have this height of
two so as we get close to any point a
because it's just this straight line
that the height of it is going to be a
as and so the limit of the function X as
the variable X goes to a is just going
to be equal to a okay what about all
this nonsense we've got a whole polom
inside of here what we get to do is we
get to use these different rules these
limit laws to very quickly figure this
out and I'm going to go slowly this
first time but in a moment we're just
going to answer this
immediately the idea is first see was a
sum of three different things and we saw
that the limit of a sum was the sum of
the limits so I can break that up as the
sum of three different things the sum of
this first 3x cubed the sum of the X and
the sum of the minus one it's the it's
three different limits and we figured
out what the limit of a constant was and
the limit of x was we know both of those
and I'm also going to try to break this
one up notice we got a scalar and we got
a product X cubed is like x * x * X so
then when I Advance this what we're
going to have is first of all the the
triple product x * x * X is three
different limits here the scaler gets bu
built out of the front that was one of
our rules and then for the limit of x
and limit of the minus one I just plug
in those values we just saw the A and
the minus
one and now I've taken the X Cub down to
a limit of x X we just seen what that
was you plug in a and so what we're
going to get is 3 a cub + the Aus 1 in
other words what we've done here is we
just took this a that was there and we
just just plugged it in 3x Cub + x - 1
became 3 a cub + Aus one so polinomial
are really easy there's nothing to do
with a polinomial not have to graph it
you just plug the value in and indeed
it's true even slightly more General
it's true for something called rational
function so this is a rational function
f ofx it's a polinomial on the top and a
polom on the bottom and as long as you
don't have the polinomial at this point
a being equal to zero because you'd have
some sort of division by zero thing the
limit is super easy you just plug the
value in whatever rational function you
might have its limit is you just take
that a that you're taking the limit to
and you plug it in the same way this
polinomial we just plugged it in so for
a ton of these values as long as you
don't have a zero on the bottom as long
as you don't have that problem spot that
for these rational functions limits are
really easy you just plug them in